MEHADI HASSAN SAKI

DATA ANALYST



Savar, Dhaka- 1343

mehsaki@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/mehadisaki

github.com/mehadisaki

+88-0191-7522698

PROFILE

Entry-level Data analytics professional; recently completed the M.Sc in Applied statistics and Data science.

Ten years of experience and comprehensive knowledge of Datadriven decision-making and Data analysis in the manufacturing industry with solid academic background.

I have strong leadership experience in project management, team management, and operation management.

I hope that build my career as a Data analyst, Business Intelligence analyst, or operation manager within a forward-thinking company.

EXPERIENCES

October' 2022

The Spark Foundation

Intern in Data Science and Business **Analytics**

- Analyse Data and make a Data model as per the requirement
- Work on supervised, and unsupervised learning
- Exploratory data analysis by BI tools
- Use python, ML algorithm, and Tableau

2016- present

Walton Hi-Tech Industries Ltd

R&D Engineer

- Analyse the process to increase productivity and reduce process loss as a Process Development team leader.
- Analyze and prepare data model based on Market feedback and after-sales service data
- DFMEA (Design Failure Mode & Effects Analysis) and Root cause analysis of product and process to improve quality

2011-2016

Pran-RFL Group

Asst. Manager (Operation)

- Performed as Operational Head of metal Products
- Market demand and fault analyze
- Guide to developed and maintained products quality

TRAINING

Topics: Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate Institute: Google | Year: Running (completed 7 of 8)

Topics: Introduction to Tableau Institute: DataCamp | Year: 2022

Topics: Machine Learning A-Z™: Hands-On Python & R In Data

Science

Institute: Udemy | Duration: 48 hr | Year: 2022

Topics: Microsoft Project Course

Institute: Project Management Solution BD

Year: 2021

EDUCATION

Jahangirnagar University

2019 - 2021 | Master's is Applied Statistics and Data Science with thesis. Link

Khulna University of Engineering & Technology Khulna | 2007-2011

2007-2011 | Bachelor in Mechanical Engineering

SKILLS

Specialties:

- Data analysis,
- Relational databases and SQL
- Data visualization skills
- Machine learning
- Business Intelligence
- Project management

Technical Skills:

• Data Visualization: Tableau, Power BI

• Programming: Python, R, SQL

Spreadsheets

• Database: BigQuery

• Team management: MS Project

LANGUAGES

English Professional Working

Turkish Elementary

REFERENCES

Engr. Rakibuzzaman Babna COO | RFL- Furniture babname02@gmail.com +88-0167-5723455

Scan here to open my resume. Or visit

